DATTATRAY DHAYGUDE

+91 9960917593 * Pune, India

dattatraysdhaygude@gmail.com * linkedin.com/in/dattatray-dhaygude/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Performance driven professional with data passionate over 8 years of rich and extensive experience in Data Analytics, specializing in the BFSI, FMCG and Textile industry. I have a strong background in data analysis, database management, and Business Intelligence tools with the ability to translate business requirements into technical solutions. Ability to Identify opportunities which add value to the business and make the process more efficient. Strong analytical thinking with problem solving approach and good ability to understand new data sources in short timeframe & embed them into standard analyses.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Infiiloom India Pvt Ltd | Consultant Data Analytics| *Python, Power BI, Excel, SAP* |

Jan 2024 - till now

- Identifying the technical gaps in the existing processes for procurement, planning and delivery from a financial perspective and make recommendations for improvement to the company
- Responsible for designing, developing and maintaining Financial Dashboard also monitoring the Dashboard on real time basis.
- Provide timely metrics reports and status updates on assigned requisitions for Planning and forecasting.

Bajaj Markets | Manager - BIU Analytics | SQL, Excel, Python, Adobe Analytics, Amazon AWS |

Jul 2021- Aug 2023

- Collaborated cross functional teams to improve productivity and resolve challenging business issues.
- Successfully scaled businesses, achieved historical card numbers and increased sales volume growth, resulting significant profit gains.
- Developed a **classification model** with **85% accuracy** in predicting credit card approval, leading to a **15% increase** in streamline offer match process and a **10% improvement** in revenue.

Desai Brothers Ltd | Senior Data Analyst | Excel, Python, SQL, Power Point Presentation, ERP |

Jul 2021- Jun 2021

- Analyze business processes, identify areas for improvement, and propose solutions to enhance efficiency and effectiveness.
- Responsible for B2B and B2C sales growth planning, Vehicle cost optimization, Customer churn and retention.
- Prepare detailed business reports and presentations for senior management. Handle confidential and sensitive information.
- Analyzed customer footfall, purchasing pattern and behavior of products to improve sales volume **250** metric ton to **500** metric ton with constant three-month performance.
- Continuously track competitors' strategy and adapt quickly for better business growth and grow the market share, create and sustain brand value. identify critical business Area sales and control vehicle cost, business margin, business promotion activity.

Baja Auto Finance, Bajaj Finserv | Data Associate, Product Executive | SQL, Excel |

Jun 2016- Apr 2018

- Responsible for Two-wheeler Sales Reports and maintain Annual operating plan.
- Collect and analyze large datasets to identify trends, patterns and insights, develop ad hoc reports and dashboards to communicate insights to Marketing Head.
- Monitor the Sales performance hourly & understand the customer facing problem using water fall to coordinate IT team & tackle fraud related issue.
- Collaborated with marketing campaigns teams for sharp shoot campaign on selected audience for better conversion for helpful control campaigns cost.

EDUCATION

T C College, Baramati | R, Minitab, MATLAB, R Shiny, Excel |

2011 - 2013

Bachelor of Science, Statistics | Percentage - 60.17% |

Pune

SKILLS

Frameworks: Python, R, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn,

Databases : MySQL, Postgre SQL, SQL Server

Tools : GitHub, Jupiter Notebook, Excel, Power BI, Tableau, Excel, Adobe Analytics, Amazon AWS

Soft Skills : Problem Solving, Analytical thinking, Stake holder management, Strategic Planning, proactively working

CERTIFICATE/ACHIEVEMENTS

- Successfully completed company organized certification program (Tableau, Postgres SQL)
- Awarded by "Good Job Done Letter" in outstanding Chips and Namkeen sales performance using Data Analysis.
- Awarded by "Spot Award" for streamline offer match process of Credit Card.